CHRISTOPHE FOYER

christophe@cfoyer.com • linkedin.cfoyer.com • US: (+1) 816-419-6150 | UK: (+44) 7444 175493 US and French citizenship | Eligible to work without restriction in the USA, UK, and EEA

SUMMARY

Engineer with experience in projects in involving mechatronics and software development. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to technical challenges.

- Software Development and Data Analysis
- 3D Simulations, CAD, FEA and CFD

Engineering Calculations

Mechatronics, Prototyping, and Fabrication

EXPERIENCE

Temporary Works Design

Design Engineer

London, United Kingdom Nov 2018 – July 2019

TWD is an engineering company specialized in creating custom-designed tools and structures to perform transport and installation projects.

- Design of bespoke equipment and structures for offshore installation projects using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis
- Contributed to custom calculation standardization software projects to improve engineering workflow

Tata Steel Europe

Engineering Intern – Student SWAT team

IJmuiden, Netherlands Apr 2018 – July 2018

Tata Steel is Europe's second largest steel producer, with steelmaking in the UK and Netherlands, and manufacturing plants across Europe.

- Successfully built a large-scale thermal simulation in Python reducing temperature estimation error by 82.4%
- Proof-of-concept currently under direct implementation by a KPMG team at Tata Steel IJmuiden.
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Founder

Washington University in St. Louis Mar 2016 - Dec 2017

WUDBF is an aerospace-oriented engineering team that attends yearly competitions that are sponsored by the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA).

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Gathered over \$10,000 worth of funding in our inaugural year with the team growing to over 40 members today

EDUCATION

University College London

Master of Science - Scientific Computing

London, United Kingdom Sep 2019 – Sep 2020

Washington University in Saint Louis

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering | Minor in Energy Engineering

Saint Louis, USA Aug 2014 - Dec 2017

- RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017) – Energy & Mechatronics

- School for International Training, Iceland (Summer 2015) - Energy

SKILLS

CAD / FEA / CFD SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, Fusion 360, XFLR5 **Programming** Python, MATLAB, Linux, C++, Simulink, JavaScript, ROS

Prototyping 3D-Printing, GD&T, Basic Machining (mill, lathe), Composite wet layup (FG/CF)

Native English and French (Bilingual) • Basic German and Icelandic Languages

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

M.Sc. Thesis – B-Spline Active Contours (computer vision & optimization) B.S. Final Project – Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics (energy & optics) Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017